# Web / Software Developer



Shimul Shil



42347239



shimul\_ustc@yahoo.com



Rebæk Søpark 25, 3TV 2650 Hvidovre



www.linkedin.com/in/shimul-shil



https://shimul-portfoliobootstrap.netlify.app

### **Professional Skills**

- HTML
- CSS/Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- React Js
- Angular
- Node Js
- PHP
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- ML (MLFlow)
- Shopify

### **Knowledge On**

- TCP/IP
- LAN / WAN
- Ionic-5
- Photoshop
- React-360
- Figma
- Wordpress
- UX Design
- Git & Bitbucket
- Microsoft Planner
- Trello

### **Professional Profile**

Solution-driven web developer adept at contributing, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction in a highly collaborative work environment. Proven experience in building user-friendly web applications using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React JS, Angular and Node JS.

Most recently, I developed a web application with React Js and Material UI on my internship project. Currently, I am working on some projects out of curiosity to learn React JS and React UI libraries in depth. Such projects will help me gain better opportunities in a real environment and the ability to self-manage independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

My greatest strength is quick learning and adapt new environment.

#### **Personal competence**

- Initiative
- Team work
- Curious & Helpful
- Analytical and organizing
- Problem Solving

- Responsibility
- Strong in decision making
- Planning of work assignments
- Strong communicator
- Focusing on deadlines

### **Education**

Top-up Bachelor's degree - Web Development Zealand Institute of Business and Technology, Roskilde, Denmark. <a href="https://zealand.com/">https://zealand.com/</a>

February 2021 - June 2022

**Vocational Web Developer** 

Roskilde Tekniske Skole, Roskilde, Denmark.

https://www.rts.dk/

August 2020- January-2021 (Grundforløbets -2)

Masters in Electrical Engineering (Telecommunication), Blekinge Institute of Technology, Sweden.

https://www.bth.se/eng/

October 2008- December 2010

Bachelor in Computer Science & Engineering, University of Science & Technology Chittagong, Bangladesh. https://www.ustc.ac.bd/

January 2001- December 2005

# **Dissertation Project Works**

#### **Machine Learning tool (MLFlow)**

**Objective**: To find the best ML tool **(MLFlow)** based on the needs of the company and to implement ML process in Windows and Linux environment.

## Language Skills

- English Fluent in all aspect
- Bengali Native
- Danish Intermediate

## **Aktivities/ Volunteering**

Active member of event organizing and leadership committee of Bengali Cultural Association (BCAS) from 2013.

Member of Non-profit Organization UNICEF as a financial supporter from 2014, to saves children's lives, defends their rights, and helps them fulfill their potential.

## **Driving License**

Category-B

#### Interests

- Travelling
- Social work
- Playing Badminton
- · Playing Football
- · Long driving
- Camping

## **Internship Project Works**

#### **Create GUI Monitoring Web Application**

**Objective**: Create a web base monitoring application for the QS2/HT Condor engine.

Using React JS & Material UI

# **Institutional Project Works**

### Synopsis- Semester project with React Js

https://to-do-list-redux-react.netlify.app/ Using React Js & Bootstrap

### WebShop- PHP semester project

http://shimul.dk/webshop

Using HTML, CSS, PHP & Bootstrap

### **Mental Shower- Semester project**

https://mentalshower.mi-designstudio.com/selection Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ionic-5 & Angular

### Individual-Project-Shop

https://sko-butik-project.netlify.app

Using HTML, CSS & JavaScript

Dice- Game -

https://dice-game-project.netlify.app/

Using HTML, CSS, JavaScript & PHP

### RTS-uw-uddennelser-

https://rts-uw-uddennelser.netlify.app

Using HTML, CSS & JavaScript

# **Work Experience**

Web Developer (Intern)- Hexagon Geosystems Services. Søborg 2860, Denmark.

Jan 2022- June 2022

#### Team Member- DHL Aviation.

Kastrup, Denmark.

December 2015- September 2019.

Service Assistant, Børne-og-Ungdemsforvaltningen.

Copenhagen Kommune, Denmark.

April 2014 - April 2016

Freelance IT-Supporter, Shetty Foundation.

Chittagong, Bangladesh.

December 2010- July 2012

**Network Support Executive, Worldye Dress Pants Itd.** Chittagong, Bangladesh.

June 2006 - July 2008